Marco Guerrieri

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS



London, United Kingdom



ITA +39 3482929965 UK +44 7542294264



marcoguerrieri@gmail.com

LINKS



Personal Website



LinkedIn



GitHub



Medium

MAIN SKILLS

Swift

Objective-C

Python

Java

Kotlin

Javascript

HTML + CSS

LANGUAGES

Italian

English

Native

Fluent

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree **Computer Science** University of Turin, Italy

PROFILE

Senior Software Engineer, in the IT world since 2013.

Pragmatic, precise and productive developer, focused on creating software with clean architectures, great code readability and extensive use of Unit and Snapshot testing.

Experience in leading dev teams, technical customer interactions and management roles.

As a developer, iOS Apps with AGILE methodology are my main field, but I have highlighted great adaptability in my career managing to use various technologies and languages (Python, Java, Kotlin, Javascript and more) to create Android apps, mobile hybrid frameworks and act as a full-stack developer when needed.

I always seek the opportunity to create user-centered, reliable and maintainable products, and at the same time conceive and propose solutions and features for their improvement.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

SENIOR IOS ENGINEER

Kin+Carta (London, United Kingdom)

JANUARY 2019 — PRESENT

- Tech Lead on international projects where I gathered and documented information about the ways of working, the client infrastructure and their business logic. Discussed and documented new API contracts, had daily meetings with the client PO, assisted the developers and testers teams on technical and logical problems, reviewed iOS pull requests.
- · Lead iOS Developer of B2C applications for major national and international companies, responsible for the iOS code base, leading and managing the iOS team, code reviews, code refactoring and modularisation. Daily team meetings and frequent interactions with customers for technical decisions and development planning. Conceived, proposed and implemented various features and improvements for the final product, as well as having improved performance and user interface. All projects followed Agile methodologies with continuous integration and extensive Unit and Snapshot testing. When possible, also paying attention to accessibility. Main architectures used were MVVM, MVP, Viper and some personalized hybrids.
- · Line manager of other engineers helping them in their career development. Monthly one-to-one meetings to outline the objectives to be achieved, personal advice and technical lessons. Also responsible for collecting feedback on their work and writing biannual reviews for promotions and career growth.

iOS TEAM LEADER

AizoOn Consulting (Torino, Italy)

FEBRUARY 2018 — OCTOBER 2018

- iOS Team Leader for an IoT application made to remotely control security systems and security cameras, with live streaming and home automation. Led the iOS team developments with technical decisions, code review, daily customer interaction for technical issues and development planning, codebase refactors and various big performance improvements of the app.
- Full Stack Software Developer responsible for the improvement of the IoT connection framework written in Clanguage, the frontend part in HTML, CSS and Javascript, and the backend side built in PHP and SQL.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Elipse (Torino, Italy)

May 2013 — FEBRUARY 2018

Main roles:

- Mobile Software Developer of various iOS and Android apps and frameworks using mainly Swift, Objective-C and Java for Android
- Full Stack Software Developer of various B2C portals using mainly Python and Java for the backend part, and HTML, CSS, Javascript and JQuery for the frontend side.
- Project Manager in consultancy in an international company for their internal sales leads portal, acting also as backend and frontend software developer